{"tossups": [{}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "For ten points, name this city, the target of two Ottoman sieges, the center of Hapsburg Austria.", "answer": "<b><u>Vienna</u></b> (accept <b><u>Wien</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "For ten points, name this king of England who fathered Richard the Lionheart and John.", "answer": "<b><u>Henry II</u></b> of England (prompt on Henry)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b><u>Three bright arcs around this object were named for the motto of the French Revolution.</u></b> <b><u>George Airy was blamed for the British team failure to discover this object first after Johann</u></b> <b><u>Galle used calculations by Urbain Le (+)</u>  Verrier to do so. This planet, whose largest moon is Triton, was the final one visited by </b><em><b>Voyager 2</b></em><b>, which observed a Great (*) </b>Dark Spot on  it. For ten points, name this planet that, after the demotion of Pluto, regained its status as the farthest  planet from the Sun.", "answer": "<b><u>Neptune</u></b>", "metadata": "Science - Other Science - Astronomy"}, {"question": "<b><u>This man wrote about the noble savage Hayy in his treatise</u> </b><em><b><u>The Christian Philosopher</u> </b></em><b><u>,</u></b> <b><u>the first book of science published in the Americas. This man, whose father served as</u></b> <b><u>President of (+)</u>  Harvard for two decades and fought against governor-dictator Edmund Andros, supported smallpox inoculation in New England. The (*) </b>executions of colonists during  the Salem Witch Trials were supported by, for ten points, what son of Increase, a Puritan minister during  the First Great Awakening?", "answer": "Cotton <b><u>Mather</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>John Stuart Mill claimed that this battle, \u201cev</u><u>en as an</u><u> event in British history, is</u></b> <b><u>more important than the Battle of Hastings.\u201d Ctesias</u> [tee-sus]<u>and Herodotus disagree over</u></b> <b><u>whether a general who had earlier sacked Eretria, Dat</u><u>is, was (</u><u>+)</u>  killed at this battle. Eleven Plataeans were killed at this battle, where troops of the Leontis tribe were commanded by Themistocles. (*) </b>Miltiades [mill-TIE-uh-deez] led the winners of this battle, after which Pheidippides  [fay-uh-DIP-uh-deez] delivered the news to Athens. For ten points, name this 490 BC battle that inspired  a modern 26 mile race.", "answer": "Battle of <b><u>Marathon</u></b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This philosopher once studied under the Earl of Shaftesbury, who he also served as a</u></b> <b><u>physician. In one book, this philosopher developed a theory of identity based on memory;</u></b> <b><u>in another book he argued for tolerance for everyone but Catholics and (+)</u>  atheists. This author of </b><em><b>A Letter Concerning Toleration </b></em><b>developed the idea of the (*) </b><em>tabula rasa</em> in <em>An</em> <em>Essay Concerning Human Understanding</em>. For ten points, name this English empiricist who defended the right to revolution in <em>Two Treatises on Government</em>.", "answer": "John <b><u>Locke</u></b>", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {"question": "<b><u>The first battle in this conflict arose after merchants aboard the</u> </b><em><b><u>Thomas Coutts</u> </b></em><b><u>signed</u></b> <b><u>a trade bond despite orders to the contrary, prompting the (+)</u> </b> <em><b>Hyacinth </b></em><b>and </b><em><b>Volage </b></em><b>to blockade a nearby town. During this war, a letter asking \u201cwhere is your conscience\u201d was addressed to one side\u2019s monarch by Lin (*)</b>Zexu. This conflict ended in the Treaty of Nanking  which ceded Hong Kong to Great Britain. The Qing were defeated in, for ten points, what 1839 war over  the trade of a namesake drug.", "answer": "<b><u>First Opium War</u></b> (prompt on Opium War)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b><u>The idea of an \u201cinfamous\u201d crime as stated in this amendment is clarified in</u> </b><em><b><u>Green v.</u></b></em> <em><b><u>United States</u></b></em><b><u>. Eminent domain with \u201cjust compensation\u201d is allowed by this amendment\u2019s</u></b> <b><u>Takings Clause, and another part of this amendment declares that (+)</u>  life, liberty and property cannot be deprived without due process. </b><em><b>Miranda </b></em><b>warnings are required for this amendment\u2019s right against (*)</b>self incrimination to be upheld. Defendants may plead, for ten points,  whatearlyConstitutionalamendmentthatdealswithcriminalprocedure?", "answer": "<b><u>5</u></b>th Amendment to the US Constitution", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This composer wrote a theme and variations for piano and orchestra on Mozart\u2019s aria</u></b> <b><u>\u201cL</u><u>`</u><u>a</u><u>ci darem la mano.\u201d This composer wrote a piano piece in response to the revolutions of</u></b> <b><u>1848</u><u>that</u><u>was</u><u>nicknamed</u><u>(+)</u>  \u201cHeroic\u201dbyhislover,GeorgeSand.Thiscomposer\u2019spersonal</b> <b>responsetothe1831NovemberUprisingwashis(*) </b> <em>E\u00b4tudeontheBombardmentofWarsaw</em>. For ten points, name this foremost composer of mazurkas, the Polish-born composer of the <em>Minute Waltz</em> and <em>RevolutionaryE\u00b4tude</em>.", "answer": "Fr\u00b4ed\u00b4eric (Fran\u00b8cois) <b><u>Chopin</u></b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "<b><u>This monarch negotiated the return of Calais by signing the Treaty of Vervins with</u></b> <b><u>Philip II. The Battle of Ivry, a decisive battle with the (+)</u>  Catholic League, was won by this monarch. This man, after defeating the Duke of Guise, legendarily converted to Catholicism by saying that (*)</b>\u201cParis is well worth a mass.\u201d The Bourbon Dynasty was founded by  this man who ended the French Wars of Religion. For ten points, name this French King who granted  Huguenots religious freedom in the Edict of Nantes.", "answer": "<b><u>Henry IV</u></b> of France (accept <b><u>Good King Henry</u></b>; accept <b><u>Henry the Great</u></b>; accept <b><u>Henry</u></b> <b><u>III of Navarre</u></b>; prompt on Henry) <b>Extra Question </b> Only read if you need a backup or tiebreaker!", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This man may have been killed by his former supporter Ta Mok after being placed</u></b> <b>under house arrest for murdering Son Sen. Upon taking power, this man transformed <u>a (+)</u>  high school into a torture-center called S-21. This successor of Lon (*) </b>Nol reset his country\u2019s calendar to \u201cYear Zero.\u201d A failed 1975 invasion of Vietnam ended the rule of this man who had ordered the execution of millions in civilians in the \u201ckilling fields.\u201d For ten points, name this Cambodian leader of the Khmer Rouge.", "answer": "<b><u>Pol Pot</u></b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}